<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nlp on bcdata</title>
    <link>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2018/tags/nlp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nlp on bcdata</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 bcdata.ca</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2018/tags/nlp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing network performance and user opinion of a VoIP PBX.</title>
      <link>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2018/project/project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2018/project/project-5/</guid>
      <description>Mentor: Graham Nelson-Zutter, CloudPBX Summary Canada is a member of the G8 and like other leading industrialized nations it offers relatively high speed and stable internet access to the to the majority of its urban population. As with other G8 citizens, Canadians benefit from all of the modern services that the high speed internet access can provide. Among many other real-time services on the internet, voice-over-IP (VoIP) is quickly becoming a prefered way for Canadians and Canadian businesses to access telephone services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Determining intent and automating knowledge base creation from live chat transcripts.</title>
      <link>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2018/project/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2018/project/project-4/</guid>
      <description>Mentor: David Carlson and Kevin Gao, Comm100 Summary Natural Language Processing (NLP) is being dramatically enhanced by AI and machine learning. We believe NLP is at the tipping point, about to reach a level of performance accuracy that makes widespread commercial applications more dependable. The challenge is in quickly training bots on common lexicon, intent, and reaction. The data set provided includes thousands of online chat sessions between support and sales agents of a company and their customers or online web visitors.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>