<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks on bcdata</title>
    <link>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2018/talk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks on bcdata</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 bcdata.ca</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2018/talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Reception</title>
      <link>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2018/talk/reception/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 16:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2018/talk/reception/</guid>
      <description>Reception Please join us for a post-presentation reception on Friday June 8 at 16:00 in the PIMS Lounge (ESB 4133). Please check back for more information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Final presentations</title>
      <link>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2018/talk/final-presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2018/talk/final-presentations/</guid>
      <description>Industry project presentations There will be a lunch for participants and industry mentors in ESB 2012 from 12:00 to 13:00. Afterwards, students will present their work to industry mentors in a 20 minute presentation (plus 10 minutes for questions) in ESB 2012. Please see the table below for a schedule.
Participants: Please send your project titles (and abstracts) to
aberk@math.ubc.ca before 18:00 on Thursday June 7.
   Start End Group Project title     13:00 13:30 CloudPBX Quality Analysis of CloudPBX VoIP Calls   13:30 14:00 Comm100 Predicting Message Paths and Determining Conversation Intent from Live Chat Transcripts   14:00 14:30 SNC-Lavalin Interpolating Ship Paths   14:30 15:00 &amp;ndash;break&amp;ndash;    15:00 15:30 St.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop Dinner</title>
      <link>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2018/talk/pizza-dinner/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2018/talk/pizza-dinner/</guid>
      <description>Workshop dinner Please join us for a pizza dinner on Thursday June 7 at 18:00, in the IAM lounge (LSK 311).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Career Panel at KPMG</title>
      <link>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2018/talk/career-panel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2018/talk/career-panel/</guid>
      <description>--  Video recording of career panel.  Summary On the evening of June 6th, BC Data Science workshop participants gathered at KPMG headquarters for a career panel and social event. The panel discussed non-academic career options for math-inclined folk; how to be prepared for industry jobs and job interviews; and what differences to expect in industry. More broadly, the panelists discussed career success, personal values, and strategies for achieving career-oriented goals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Full schedule</title>
      <link>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2018/talk/full-schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2018/talk/full-schedule/</guid>
      <description>Schedule The introductory and closing remarks of the workshop will take place in the UBC Earth Sciences Building, as per the schedule below. The projects for the workshop will take place in the UBC Orchard Commons building. Event rooms at this location will be clarified in the table below or during the introductory remarks. Relevant content for each project can be found in the GitHub repository for the workshop, and on bcdata.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Registration deadline</title>
      <link>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2018/talk/registration-deadline/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2018/talk/registration-deadline/</guid>
      <description>The deadline for registration for the workshop is 15 May 2018. To register for the workshop and the pre-workshop, please visit the link above.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>