<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Machine Learning on bcdata</title>
    <link>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/tags/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Machine Learning on bcdata</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 bcdata.ca</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 09:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 2: Advanced Topics</title>
      <link>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/post/advanced-topics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/post/advanced-topics/</guid>
      <description>Description In the mornings of the second week of the workshop, we will host advanced lectures on topics pertaining to data science. These talks are expected to be more academic in nature, showcasing research and research tools used by professors in either academia or industry. Speaker bios and abstracts can be found below. For lectures notes and other materials, please visit the GitHub repository for the workshop.
Talks Inferring the Past for Traits that Alter Speciation and Extinction Speaker: Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Insights from Vehicle Time Series Messages</title>
      <link>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/project/project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 11:33:44 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/project/project-5/</guid>
      <description>Mentor: Borhan Sanandaji Summary  Idea 1: Characterize and visualize the make/model/year distribution in the dataset; extend this by characterizing the conditional distribution over the geographical span of the dataset.
 Idea 2: Determinine the devices in the dataset that have multiple drivers per mojio device
 Idea 3: (Optional) Using any of the existing variables in the dataset or outside resources, forecast the battery voltage of the vehicles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elucidating enhancer-promoter gene expression using ConvNets</title>
      <link>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/project/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/project/project-3/</guid>
      <description>Mentor: Cory Simon Summary Different cell types in humans possess approximately the same genome despite having dramatically different functions. Gene regulation is the complex process by which cells selectively synthesize different proteins encoded in their genome. [1] A fundamental understanding of how genes are regulated can lead towards effective treatments for cancers and developmental disorders.
Enhancers are distal regulatory elements that, in conjunction with a promoter, recruit the proteins required to drive transcription of a gene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-Resolution Shoreline Data for Flood Protection and Environmental Conservation</title>
      <link>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/project/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/project/project-4/</guid>
      <description>Mentor: Nathan Vadeboncoeur Summary Canada should be the world leader in coastline management. We have, by far, the longest coastline of any country and more lakes than the rest of the world combined. Communities from coast-to-coast-to-coast have been managing flood risks and supporting important ecosystems for generations, but much of this knowledge isn’t shared. This is because data often come with restrictions that limit sharing, and are in a format that requires expensive and specialized software to access.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A risk-based platform for accident prevention</title>
      <link>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/project/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/project/project-2/</guid>
      <description>Mentor: Soyean Kim, BC Safety Authority Summary BC Safety Authority’s accident prevention strategy follows a risk based platform, called “bow tie” for ongoing management and prevention of major incidents. The bow tie method draws on the direct experience of safety management team and the data collected from various safety oversight programs in order to identify hazards and to properly incorporate critical controls into management systems. In addition, it raises awareness and improves understanding and risk knowledge of the potential major incidents and the reliance on critical controls that prevent those accidents from occurring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data-driven modeling of video compression</title>
      <link>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/project/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2017/project/project-1/</guid>
      <description>Mentor: Roger Donaldson, Midvale Applied Mathematics Summary Despite our hand in their design, and hence their seemingly deterministic operation, electronic systems grow ever more complex and are often most simply characterized through measurement-driven modeling. This workshop presents measurements of the rate at which bits are produced as output of a compression algorithm for a digital video camera. The data are produced by presenting the camera with a variety of test scenes, and operating it over a variety of settings.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>