<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data on bcdata</title>
    <link>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2018/tags/data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data on bcdata</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 bcdata.ca</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 19:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2018/tags/data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The 2018 PIMS BC Data Science Workshop</title>
      <link>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2018/post/workshop-description/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2018/post/workshop-description/</guid>
      <description>Overview This workshop will host 50 students from PIMS institutions and interested industry members for a two week foray into foundational and crucial elements of the rapidly expanding field of data science.
For lecture notes, code and other workshop materials, please visit the associated GitHub repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimal sales strategy for heavy freight shipping</title>
      <link>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2018/project/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://workshop.bcdata.ca/2018/project/project-1/</guid>
      <description>Mentor: Bernard Chan, BuildDirect Summary About BuildDirect BuildDirect is the first technology platform for the home improvement industry. The BuildDirect platform includes two core business units:
 BuildDirect Marketplace: An online marketplace that offers Pro Buyers and Homeowners the ability to purchase heavyweight home improvement products direct from Sellers and receive efficient direct-to-home (or jobsite) shipping of those products. Gateway Supply Chain: The first anywhere-to-the-home supply chain for heavy and bulky goods that equips manufacturers, distributors and retailers with efficient and cost-effective shipping solutions to move their products from anywhere in the world, to locations across North America.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>